Hello, and welcome back. We actually see inpainting in nature all
【未完成版本】大家好 在生活中我们总能接触到图像修复技术
the time. Let me show you some examples.
这节课中 我将展示一些例子
What do you see here? You'll probably see a rock, and nothing
这里你看到了什么？你可能看到了一块石头 而且除了石头什么都没有
else than a rock. But there's actually something hiding in
但是在石头上确实隐藏着东西
that rock. Let me just show that to you, or at least
我在这将会给大家展示 或者至少帮助大家看到它
help you to see it. There is actually a fish hiding in that
其实在石头上 藏着一条鱼
rock. You might be able to see it. I hope you
你可能已经看到了
do, but I'm going to help you.
我希望你已经看到了 但是我将进一步引导你
You can see the eyes here, you can see the tailfin here. The whole fish is in
大家可以看到这是眼睛 这里是尾巴 整个鱼是这一部分
here. Pretty amazing isn't it?
很惊人不是吗？
That's camouflage, but that's also inpainting.
这是伪装 但也像是一种修补
The fish has inpainted itself in order to get camouflage.
这条鱼改变颜色来伪装自己
It has basically, it's kind of object removal in nature.
这是一种自然界中的物体去除
Pretty amazing. We also see that with octopuses.
非常惊人 我们知道章鱼也可以这样
I'm going to give you another example of how amazing this fish is.
我将会给大家展示另一个例子 说明这种鱼有多么令人惊讶
This is not a very high quality image, but still it's going to illustrate how
这幅图像的质量不高 但也可以说明这种鱼有多么令人惊讶
amazing this fish is. The fish was now, not in nature as
现在 这条鱼并不像先前那样在自然环境中
before, but basically in a very nice fish tank, was basically put, an experiment
而是在一个漂亮的鱼缸里
done by Ramachandran and collaborators, on top of polka dots.
这是一个由拉玛钱德朗(Ramachandran) 和他的合作者 利用圆点图来完成的一个实验
So it's basically a piece of paper or basically something that is colored with
实际上 就是在一张纸上 或者其他的物体上画上点
dots, as we see here. It's very interesting that if you have
就像我们可以看到的这样 从现在开始 会非常有趣
started here, for example, the fish has turned around, has created two polka
举个例子 这条鱼转过身 已经在它的身上制造了两个圆点
dots. In its own body.
在它自己的身上
And once again I apologize for the relatively low quality of this image that
再次 我为这个图像的低质量表示抱歉
was scanned from a paper. It's just kind of a long process to get
因为这幅图是由纸板扫描得到的 将图像输入计算机的处理过程很长
it into the computer. And it's also turning around to put
这条鱼还转过身来
basically its eyes on top of one of the polkadots.
把它的眼睛对准其中的一个圆点
So basically the fish is trying to ("inpaint) himself,
实际上 这条鱼是在”修补“它自身
trying to camouflage itself so it cannot be seen by predators.
力图伪装自己 不被食肉动物看到
So we see inpainting in nature, fish, octopuses and others.
我们看到自然界里的修补现象 比如鱼、章鱼还有其他动物
We actually are doing inpainting all the time.
事实上 我们也一直在修补
When you are watching this video, you're actually doing in painting.
当你看这段视频的时候 你就正在做着修复工作
Why is that? When we have, when we remember that we
为什么会这样呢 当我们修复的时候 还记得我们
learn about the human eye, in the retina, in the back of the eye there's a region
学习人类眼睛的时候 在视网膜中 在眼睛后方有一个区域
with no sensors, no sensors at all. No cones, no rods.
【未完成版本】没有感应器 完全不能感知 没有视锥细胞和视感细胞
That is kind of the region where the sensors basically send the cables back to
这个区域供感应器向后传输电波给大脑
the brain. So there's actually no sensors.
所以这部分没有感应器
So what should happen if you have no sensors?
如果没有感应器会发生什么呢？
We should actually see a hole in the visual world, where basically you would
我们会在视觉世界里看到一个洞
be watching this video and there would kind of a region of missing information
在观看视频的时候 会丢失一部分区域的信息
because there are no sensors. But the humans are all the time filling
因为那个区域没有感应细胞 但是人类通过使用不同的技巧
in that region by different techniques that the visual system does and actually
不停的在填补那个区域  这是视觉系统所做
you can do those exercises. I took these images from the website that
事实上大家可以做些练习 这里展示的图片是从以下网址下载
is provided here. And the basic idea is that if you manage
基本的观点是 如果你可以紧盯住它
to fixate. Basically if you manage.
如果可以做到
You stand like a meter away from the screen and you manage to fixate the
你可以站在距离显示器大概一米远的地方 然后注视某一个点
basically a point. Like this point here.
比如说这个点
So you concentrate on fixating your visual system into that point.
你集中视觉注意力在那个点上
After a while you will see that the sun disappears.
过一会你会发现这个太阳消失了
So you're basically forcing your system to not in- paint the region that
这实际上是你在强制你的视觉系统 不再修复那个区域
basically there is no receptors. If you don't do that, if you don't
那个区域没有反应器 如果你不这样做 如果你不紧盯着它
fixate, you basically see the sun with no
毫无疑问你会看到太阳
problem. The exercise is to try to stop the visual
这个练习是试着停止视觉系统的修复
system from doing in painting. Here is another exercise you could fixate
这里还有另外一个来进行凝视的练习
here. You might be able to basically pause
你现在可以暂停一下视频
right now, or after we finish this video,
或者看完我们的视频之后
you might be able to go back, pause here, and then play with your distance to the
再回到这里 在这暂停 做这个离开显示器一段距离的游戏
screen. Fixate here, concentrate on fixating
紧盯住这里 目不转睛的盯着显示器
that, and you might be able to see, for example the ear of Van Gogh disappears,
你可能会看到 比如说梵高的耳朵消失了
or basically, the sun disappears. So you're forcing the visual system not
或者 太阳消失了 这就是你强制视觉系统不去修复的结果
to inpaint. Otherwise, we're in painting all the
否则我们就会自动进行视觉修复
times. We don't see those problems that, we
我们忽视了这些问题 是因为
don't see holes when we are looking at a scene.
我们并没有在显示器上看到空洞
So these are just examples that we actually have image and video inpainting
这就是一些我们在图像和视频中修复的例子
when we're watching at the regular scene that's basically our video coming into
当我们观看普通显示器的时候 这就是视频进入眼睛的过程
our eyes. Examples of that in nature.
这是自然界中的例子
So now we're ready to see how the computer does in painting.
现在 我们将要去看看计算机是如何做修复的
Thank you. I will see you in the next video for
谢谢大家 我们下个视频
that.
刚才我说的这些